[
  {
    "question": "A good has been added to the CPI. What conclusion BEST follows?",
    "a": "It has risen in price.",
    "b": "It is patented.",
    "c": "It is a necessity.",
    "d": "It has high market penetration.",
    "e": "It is produced domestically.",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following values are used to calculate the GDP deflator?",
    "a": "GDP and GDP per capita",
    "b": "Interest rates and GDP per capita",
    "c": "Inflation and unemployment",
    "d": "Real and nominal GDP",
    "e": "GDP and aggregate demand",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "What factor causes structural unemployment?",
    "a": "The normal process of looking for jobs",
    "b": "A mismatch between desired and available skills",
    "c": "Seasonal changes in employment opportunities",
    "d": "Fluctuations in the business cycle",
    "e": "Increased inflationary pressures",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following answer choices BEST describes a product that has a high weighting in the CPI?",
    "a": "High volume of sales",
    "b": "Significant price rise",
    "c": "Major drop in imports",
    "d": "Domestic supplier",
    "e": "New version",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following changes does the CPI influence?",
    "a": "Currency exchange rates",
    "b": "Cost-of-living adjustment",
    "c": "Medicare benefits",
    "d": "Minimum wage increases",
    "e": "Tax brackets",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "What kind of unemployment is ALWAYS present?",
    "a": "Cyclical",
    "b": "Frictional",
    "c": "Seasonal",
    "d": "Voluntary",
    "e": "Regional",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the substitution bias in the CPI?",
    "a": "Consumers’ preference for newer goods",
    "b": "Consumers’ trend-following product choices",
    "c": "Consumers’ choices of less expensive goods",
    "d": "Consumers’ irrational product preferences",
    "e": "Consumers’ desire for technological advances",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following people is out of the labor force?",
    "a": "A member of the army",
    "b": "An unemployed person searching for a job",
    "c": "A worker on sick leave",
    "d": "A frictionally unemployed graduate",
    "e": "A retiree",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Nominal inflation is 2.8%; it is 3.2% according to the CPI. The Boskin commission would place inflation at",
    "a": "3.0%",
    "b": "0.4%",
    "c": "1.9%",
    "d": "1.5%",
    "e": "3.2%",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "The working-age population includes 400 people. 64 people are not employed or seeking a job. What is the labor force participation rate?",
    "a": "16%",
    "b": "92%",
    "c": "100%",
    "d": "84%",
    "e": "64%",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does the GDP deflator differ from the CPI?",
    "a": "The GDP deflator excludes imported products.",
    "b": "The GDP deflator does not take inflation into account.",
    "c": "The GDP deflator has not been updated since 1980.",
    "d": "The GDP deflator only analyzes domestic goods.",
    "e": "The GDP deflator does not take consider CPI.",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of unemployment is strongly dependent on recessions and expansions?",
    "a": "Frictional",
    "b": "Structural",
    "c": "Seasonal",
    "d": "Cyclical",
    "e": "Involuntary",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the economic definition of the labor force?",
    "a": "The entire population of an economy",
    "b": "All people who have worked in the past four weeks",
    "c": "All employed people in an economy",
    "d": "All working-age people in an economy",
    "e": "People of working age who are working or trying to find work",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following events leads to longer periods of unemployment?",
    "a": "Increased inflation",
    "b": "Two quarters of positive economic growth",
    "c": "An increase in the minimum wage",
    "d": "A reduction in the national debt",
    "e": "Two quarters of negative economic growth",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "What labor force participation rate does the United States have?",
    "a": "100%",
    "b": "61%",
    "c": "54%",
    "d": "73%",
    "e": "32%",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following formulae is the correct formula to calculate GDP per capita?",
    "a": "Real GDP/labor force",
    "b": "Nominal GDP/labor force",
    "c": "Nominal GDP/workers",
    "d": "Nominal GDP/population",
    "e": "Real GDP/population",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following values BEST reflects growth in GDP?",
    "a": "Standard of living",
    "b": "Employment rate",
    "c": "Population growth",
    "d": "Overall prices",
    "e": "Value of production",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Relative to 1900, by what factor did US real GDP per capita rise in 2019?",
    "a": "1600%",
    "b": "400%",
    "c": "900%",
    "d": "3200%",
    "e": "2000%",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following goods is physical capital?",
    "a": "Stocks",
    "b": "Cars",
    "c": "Factories",
    "d": "Knowledge",
    "e": "Labor",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "What actor provides land and labor in economic exchange?",
    "a": "Firms",
    "b": "The government",
    "c": "Financial intermediaries",
    "d": "Natural resources",
    "e": "Households",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "To what actor do households provide income according to the circular flow model?",
    "a": "The government",
    "b": "Importers",
    "c": "Firms",
    "d": "Landlords",
    "e": "Financial intermediaries",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "What MAIN factor drives long-run productivity growth?",
    "a": "Growth in physical capital",
    "b": "Improved technology",
    "c": "Democratization",
    "d": "Legal environment",
    "e": "Discovery of natural resources",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following institutions is a firm?",
    "a": "The Federal Reserve",
    "b": "The Spanish government",
    "c": "The World Bank",
    "d": "McDonald’s",
    "e": "Doctors Without Borders",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following changes LEAST affects labor productivity?",
    "a": "Vast supplies of oil are found underground.",
    "b": "The price of gas increases.",
    "c": "A new production technique is discovered.",
    "d": "A 5G data network is rolled out.",
    "e": "Universal free education is introduced.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is NOT true of natural resources?",
    "a": "The countries with highest GDP per capita depend on natural resources.",
    "b": "Natural resources can be easily imported.",
    "c": "Iron and oil are plentiful resources that allow for economic growth.",
    "d": "Countries like Saudi Arabia depend heavily on their natural resources.",
    "e": "Natural resources are not necessary for an economy to thrive.",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is too much investment economically undesirable?",
    "a": "Investment can be inefficient and costly.",
    "b": "Investment focuses on short-run growth.",
    "c": "Investment decreases future production.",
    "d": "Investments eventually yield diminishing returns.",
    "e": "Investment decreases total welfare.",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements CORRECTLY describes the circular flow model?",
    "a": "Firms receive income.",
    "b": "The firm supplies goods and services.",
    "c": "Revenue equals wages, rent, and profits.",
    "d": "Households provide wages and labor.",
    "e": "Factors of production include income and materials.",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following decisions improves human capital?",
    "a": "Creating a human resources department",
    "b": "Upgrading the IT system",
    "c": "Holding professional development courses",
    "d": "Hiring more workers",
    "e": "Promoting a manager",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "What flow(s) does the market for goods and services experience?",
    "a": "Wages and taxes",
    "b": "Profits and rents",
    "c": "Inputs and outputs",
    "d": "Transfers and loans",
    "e": "Spending and revenue",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following countries benefited from technology transfer MOST?",
    "a": "Mexico",
    "b": "United States",
    "c": "India",
    "d": "Kenya",
    "e": "Japan",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  }
]

